

CONTACTS

- +92 312 73 78 793
- hafiz.abubakar793@gmail.com
- House 01 Block 2 B-I Township, Lahore

AWARDS

- Gold Medalist in BS Hons (Islamic Studies) session 2014-18 at Minhaj University Lahore.
- Gold Medalist in MPhil (Islamic Studies) Session 2018-20 at GC University, Lahore.
- "1st position in Badminton (College Level) 2013/14
- "Champion in Table tennis" (University Level) 2016
- "Shield of Honor" for Best performance as a President Student's Wing 2016

RESEARCH

 A critical study of Margoliouth's Muhammadenism

(Research work for the degree of MPhil Islamic Studies)

 The Role of the Scholars of Lahore in the field of Hadith

(Research work for the degree of BS Hons Islamic Studies)

Islam spread through sword or Character?

(Research Article Published in Arafat-Oct 2022)

SKILLS

- A GOOD SPEAKER (KHATEEB)
- AN EXCELLENT TEAM PLAYER
- EXCEPTIONAL ADMINISTRATION SKILLS
- A GREAT TV ANCHOR/HOST
- EXPERT IN MS OFFICE

HAFIZ

MUHAMMAD ABUBAKAR

Lecturer/Scholar Islamic Studies

GOLD MEDALIST

PROFILE

"Experienced Islamic scholar with a Master's in Islamic Studies, specializing in Shariah law and Halal research. Strong skills in analysis, writing, and publishing contemporary Shariah findings. Committed to advancing Halal knowledge through in-depth research and scholarly work."

EDUCATION

- Ph.D. in Islamic Studies
 Minhaj University, Lahore (In Progress)
- MPhil in Islamic Studies (Gold Medalist) GC University, Lahore (2020)
- Shahadatul Almia Fil Uloomal Arabia wal Islamia Jamia Islamiyah Minhaj Ul Quran, Lahore (2019)
- BS Hons in Islamic Studies (Gold Medalist) Minhaj University, Lahore (2018)
- Intermediate (A Grade) BISE Lahore (2014)
- Matriculation (A+ Grade) BISE Gujranwala (2012)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

 Lecturer | College of Shariah, Minhaj University, Lahore

March 2023 - Present

- Assistant Director Student's Affairs March 2023-Present
- Coordinator Bazm e Minhaj, COSIS
 Feb 2024-Present
- Lecturer | Superior College, Gujrat
 October 2022 March 2023
- Lecturer | University of Gujrat November 2021 – September 2022
- Lecturer | Punjab Group of Colleges (University Campus) Gujrat

December 2021 - May 2022